# **Enyel Sequeira**

<u>Linkedin</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Personal portfolio</u> | <u>enyelsequeira1994@gmail.com</u> | STL, MO +1-314-723-2857

### **SUMMARY**

Multilingual full-stack web developer with 2+ years experience, who comes from a teaching and business background and a long-standing love for learning natural languages (Spanish, Portuguese, Mandarin). Through my past experiences I can balance the need of users and businesses to understand their pain points and how I can contribute as a full-stack web developer and help them solve their problems.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, TypeScript, JavaScript Frameworks, React, Node, NextJs, Gatsby, TypeOrm, Git/GitHub, MongoDB, SQL, PSQL, Azure, AWS, CSS Frameworks, Styled-Components, SCSS, SASS, MySQL, REST, Agile, HTML

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

MovieApp - Frontend I Demo I Site

11/2020

React application using tmdb API to fetch data and using AlanAi to give some commands, such as go to actions

- Built maintainable, reusable UI components with React.
- Managed global state using Redux.
- Successfully implemented Alan AI to increase interactivity with the app.
- Using interactive AlanAI to give various functional commands.

IterativeAi - Demo I Site

11/2020

Front-end application use React Gatsby to improve SEO and overall feel and looks of previous site

- Built a fully responsive and reusable code base.
- Successfully worked in an Agile team, using Trello for task assigned and GitHub to put components together.
- Optimized SEO using Gatsby static site generator plugin.
- Designed and styled app using Styled-Components.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

HackerU, Remote 12/2020 - Current

Full-stack Web Development Instructor

- Taught web development to Wisconsin University students.
- Led classes of about 20 students and used teaching technologies to improve the learning process.
- Helped and improved teaching curriculum being used for Full-stack development.

Freelance 5/2020 - Current

Web Developer

- Designed and built sites using latest technologies such as NextJs and Gatsby.
- Performed SEO analysis of companies to better rank on Google analytics.
- Researched and improved overall sites interaction and design.

Various Institutions Universities/Schools

8/2016 - 8/2020

English Teacher

- Planned and taught English lessons to over 200 Chinese college freshmen.
- Adapted curriculum and improved English course for the English major classes.
- Helped students prepare for the TOEFL exams 10 students each semester.

## Previously | Interpreter English - Spanish | IT-Team leader - Lab-Consultant | 2012-2017

- Interpreting for companies such as IBM, Google, Facebook, Twitter.
- Assisted in providing on the job training for more than 10 new and returning consultants.

### **EDUCATION**

Practicum by Yandex I Web Engineering Program	2021
CareerFoundry I Web Development Program	2019
EUDE Business School   M.B.A Business Administration	2018
Simpson College   Global Management and Spanish	2016